Klajdi Puka, PhD

2704 - 3 Michael Power Pl Etobicoke, ON | M9A 0A2

www.kpuka.ca | klajdi.puka@gmail.com | 647-928-7852

SUMMARY OF EXPERIENCE AND QUALIFICATIONS

I am a Project Scientist at the Centre for Addiction and Mental Health (CAMH); previously, I worked as a methodologist/statistician and completed a PhD in Epidemiology and Biostatistics. Through these experiences I have worked closely with a broad range of stakeholders, providing scientific expertise, critically apprising and synthesizing information, and clearly explaining technical concepts. I have advanced knowledge of clinical and epidemiological research methods and biostatistics, and I am proficient at conveying technical details clearly and simply in accessible language. I have also built key relationships with multidisciplinary stakeholders and provided leadership by setting and overseeing the attainment of project goals, and managing competing interests, priorities and deadlines.

I am proficient with multiple statistical software packages including R, SAS, STATA, SPSS, MPlus.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Project Scientist Mar 2021 – Present Institute for Mental Health Policy Research, Toronto, ON

Centre for Addiction and Mental Health (CAMH)

• Identify and leverage nationally representative epidemiologic data, health surveys, and mortality data to support and inform public health policy.

- Design, implement, report, interpret, and publish clinical and epidemiologic studies.
- Identify, develop, and implement novel and advanced statistical methodologies.
- Appraise and synthesize relevant sources of information, and present results in scientific, technical, and lay-audience publications.
- Provide leadership and oversight to international and multidisciplinary teams to effectively manage concurrent projects, deadlines, and competing priorities.
- Build and maintain effective strategic working relationships with internal and external partners to meet project needs.
- Provide mentoring and training to students and staff.

Biostatistician Jun 2020 – Present

The Brain Recovery Project (Childhood Epilepsy Surgery Foundation)

Los Angeles, CA

- Provide scientific expertise and leadership on research methodology.
- Develop research methods based on clients' needs, and conduct advanced data analysis.
- Prepare scientific, technical, and lay-audience publications and presentations.
- Develops metrics and generates quality control reports to optimize project deliverables.
- Clearly explain technical concepts and statistical results to a broad range of stakeholders.

Statistician Jul 2018 – August 2021

Department of Medicine, Western University

London, ON

- Provided scientific expertise and leadership on research methodology, including protocol development, execution of study procedures, data analysis, and interpretation of results.
- Analyzed and interpret data using a wide variety of advanced statistical methods.

Klajdi Puka Resume

- Drafted scientific manuscripts and lay summaries to effectively communicate study results.
- Clearly explained technical concepts and statistical results to a broad range of audiences.
- Developed tools and resources to allow clients with a broad range of skills to understand and utilize basic and complex research methods and statistical methods.
- Provided leadership, train new team members, and manage competing deadlines.

Methodology and Statistics Consultant

Jan 2017 – Dec 2017

Department of Epidemiology & Biostatistics, Western University

London, ON

- Assessed clients' needs, developed study protocols, and conducted advanced data analysis.
- Provided scientific expertise and strategic advice to clients with a broad range of skillsets.
- Clearly explained and communicated technical concepts and statistical results.

PhD Candidate Sept 2016 – Apr 2021

Department of Epidemiology & Biostatistics, Western University

- Developed a research program focused on identifying and intervening on key modifiable factors important for patients' long-term health and well-being.
- Analyzed and interpret data using a wide variety of advanced statistical methods and published lay and technical summaries.
- Designed and maintained systems to facilitate research conduct and intervention delivery, as well as databases to maintain complex data structures.

Clinical Research Project Coordinator

May 2012 – Aug 2016

Department of Psychology, Hospital for Sick Children

Toronto, ON

- Coordinated and managed a wide variety of clinical research studies.
- Conducted statistical analyses and developed the knowledge translation plans.
- Designed and maintained the hospital's clinical databases.

EDUCATION

<u>Degree</u>	<u>Discipline</u>	<u>Institution</u>	<u>Years</u>
PhD	Epidemiology and Biostatistics	Western University	2016 – 2021
HBSc	Psychology and Biology	University of Toronto	2009 – 2013

SUMMARY OF RESEARCH ACCOMPLISHMENTS

- Published >40 scientific manuscripts, and 7 book chapters (most as the leading author).
- Presented in >40 scientific and lay-audience conferences.
- Taught multiple methodology/statistics courses and workshops, and developed written resources for students and trainees (available at https://kpuka.ca/resources).
- Received >\$600,000 in research funding as Principal or Co-Investigator.
- Engaged in leadership roles, as Chair, Vice-Chair and Secretary of multiple local and international committees.

My complete academic CV is available at: https://kpuka.ca/files/Klajdi Puka CV.pdf